Finding Aid for the Memorial to WillHard Brownell Jewell
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- This list includes letters written to W.B. Jewell, with the exception of letters categorised by subject, a listing of which follows the incoming correspondence list.
  - General Electric Supply Corp., 1942; l (Box 4)
  - General Science Service, 1944; 1 (Box 4)
  - Geochron Laboratories, 1960-61; 2 (Box 4)
  - The Geographical Press, 1942; 1 (Box 4)
  - Geological Publishing Co., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - The Geological Society of America, 1942-57; 17 (Box 4)
  - Geophoto Services, Inc., 1958; 1 (Box 4)
  - Geoscience Instrums. Corp., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Gerber, Jack, 1957; 1 (Box 4)
  - Giddings, Lorrain, n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Giles, H.T., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Ginn & Co., 1943; 1 (Box 4)
  - Giri, M.B.S., 1960; 1 (Box 4)
  - Glenn, L.C., 1946; 2 (Box 4)
  - Gonzajez-Reyna, J., 1953; 1 (Box 4)
  - Graves, C. Edward, 1942-49; 7 (Box 4)
  - Green Industries, 1945; 1 (Box 4)
  - Gregg, Sarah, 1951; 1 (Box 4)
  - Grieger's, n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Gude, Arthur James, III, 1948; 1 (Box 4)
  - Guffee, Harry J. (Mrs.), n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Gurley, W. & L.E., 1954; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hager, Lee, 1943; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hagerman Geologic Assocs., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Halco Scientific Instrums., 1953; 1 (Box 4)
  - Haley, Francis L., 1953; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hall, Fitzgerald, 1944; l (Box 4)
  - Hamilton, Watch Co., 1946; l (Box 4)
  - C.S. Hammond & Co., 1954; 1 (Box 4)
  - Harcourt, Brace & Co., 1943; 3 (Box 4)
  - Hardacre, Paul H., 1957; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hardeman, W.O., n.d.'s; 2 (Box 4)
  - Hardy & Co., 1958; 1 (Box 4)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1943; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hart, Henry G., 1942; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hart, Pembroke, 1956-59; 7 (Box 4)
  - Hart, Hussell E., 1953; 1 (Box 4)
  - Haun, C.C., 1954; 1 (Box 4)
  - Haupt, Charlotte, 1941; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hayes, Wayland, 1945; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hefley, Roberta, n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Henderson, Gerald D, 1931-57; 5 (Box 4)
    V.U. Bsn. Manager
  - Hennessey, Eliza, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Hinson, Vim. H., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hobbs, Hervil, n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hodges, Lilian F., 1954; 1 (Box 4)
    Office of Direc. of Admissions
  - Frank L. Howard Engineering Co., 1955; 1 (Box 4)
  - Howell, Ben F., 1928-52; 4 (Box 4)
  - Howland, Arthur L., 1951-58; 2 (Box 4)
  - Humble Oil and Refining Co., 1954; 2 (Box 4)
  - Hunt, Anne C., 1958; 1 (Box 4)
  - Hutchison, John H., 1956; 1 (Box 4)
  - Illinois, Univ. of, 1949-56; 4 (Box 4)
  - Indep. Petrol. Assoc. of Amer., 1954; 2 (Box 4)
  - International Geol. Congress, 1950-52; 2 (Box 4)
  - Intl. Magazine Co., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Jarrell-Ash Co., 1953-54; 3 (Box 4)
  - Jersey Farms Milk Service, 1942; 1 (Box 4)
  - Jewell, John (Mrs.), 1949; 1 (Box 4)
  - Johns, W.D., n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Floyd, 1947; 1 (Box 4)
  - Joint University Libraries, 1943; 3 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Earl (C.E. Jones), 1944-45; 2 (Box 4)
  - Kelley, Everett E., 1958; 1 (Box 4)
  - Kelly, W.A., 1927-52 & n.d.; 5 (Box 4)
  - Kentucky, Univ. of, 1947-52; 3 (Box 4)
  - Keuffel & Esser Co., 1953; 1 (Box 4)
  - Kewaunee Mfg. Co., 1943; 1 (Box 4)
  - Keystone View Co., 1943; 2 (Box 4)
  - Kirkland, J.H., 1930; 1 (Box 4)
  - Kraua, Edward H., 1931; 1 (Box 4)
  - Kruger, Fredrick C., 1950-53; 7 (Box 4)
    Dept. of Geol. & Geogr. -U.T. - Knoxville
  - Lagemann, Robert, 1955; 1 (Box 4)
  - Lahee, Frederic H., 1941-44; 7 (Box 4)
    Amer. Assoc. of Petrol. Geols.
  - Lambert, Dale, 1946; 1 (Box 4)
  - Karl Lambrecht - Optics, 1949; 1 (Box 4)
  - Landes, K.K., 1949; 1 (Box 4)
    Dept. of Geol. - Univ. of Mieh
  - Lapiadary Equipment Co., 1954; l (Box 4)
  - Laurence, Robert A., 1944-54; 3 (Box 4)
  - Lamb, Medora, 1952; 1 (Box 4)
  - Ledbetter, Marshall P., 1958; 1 (Box 4)
  - Lehigh University, 1957; 1 (Box 4)
  - E. Leitz, Inc., 1956; 2 (Box 4)
  - Lester, J.G., 1952-55; 3 (Box 4)
    Dept. of Geol. - Emory Univ.
  - Lewis, Fred J., 1941; 1 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, T.M.N., 1959; 1 (Box 4)
    Dept. of Anthrop. - U.T. Knoxville, Tn.
  - Liberty Mutual, 1950; 1 (Box 4)
  - Lindenmeyer, Stratton, 1953-55; 4 (Box 4)
  - Litkenhous, E.E., 1944; 1 (Box 4)
  - Long, Raymond F., 1943; 2 (Box 4)
  - Longmans, Green & Co., 1943; 2 (Box 4)
  - Louisiana State Univ, 1958; 1 (Box 4)
  - Love, Fred V., 1; 1949 (Box 4)
  - Lowman, Shepard W., 1947; 1 (Box 4)
  - Lumpkins, Caroline, 1944; 1 (Box 4)
  - The Lustro Co., n.d.; l (Box 4)
  - Lyne, Roberta Dillon, 1933; 1 (Box 4)
  - MacClintock, Paul, 1942; 1 (Box 4)
    Dept. of Geol. - Princeton Univ
  - Mackay, Donald K., 1947; 2 (Box 4)
  - Mahon, Pat, n.d.; l (Box 4)
  - Maher, Stuart W., 1955; 1 (Box 4)
  - Mailloux, Auguste, 1958; 2 (Box 4)
    Universite Laval
  - Marshall & Bruce Co., 1935; 1 (Box 4)
  - Marshall, Byron C., 1955; 1 (Box 4)
  - Martin, Clara J., 1960; 1 (Box 4)
  - Martin College, 1949; 2 (Box 4)
  - Martin, H.R., 1951; 1 (Box 4)
  - Mason, Bill, 1941; 1 (Box 4)
  - Mather, Bryant, 1955; 1 (Box 4)
  - McCampbell, John C., 1942-49; 4 (Box 4)
  - McCary, Charles, 1959; 1 (Box 4)
  - McFarlan, Arthur C., 1943-46; 2 (Box 4)
    Dept. of Geol. - Univ. of Ky.
  - McGaw, Robert A., 1948; 1 (Box 4)
    News Release Office - V.U.
  - McGraw Hill Book Co., 1943-55; 8 (Box 4)
  - McLeod, D.S., 1960; l (Box 4)
  - Mcquiddy Printing Co., 1942; 1 (Box 4)
  - Meachan, Reid P., 1933; l (Box 4)
    Bureau of Mineral & Topogr. Survey - Univ. of Ky.
  - Michigan, Univ. of, 1949; l (Box 4)
  - Miles, A.E., 1953; l (Box 4)
  - Miller, David G., 1955; l (Box 4)
  - Mineral Supply House, 1941-42 & n.d.; 5 (Box 4)
  - Minaich, Dorothy L., 1955; l (Box 4)
    Asst. to Dean of Women
  - Miser, Hugh D.9, 1931-47; 2 (Box 4)
  - Mississippi, Univ. of, 1953; l (Box 4)
  - Mistier, A.J., 1942; l (Box 4)
    U.S. Engineer Office - Charlei ton, S.c.
  - Mitchell, Raoul C., 1949; l (Box 4)
  - Molecular Models, 1942; 3 (Box 4)
  - Moneymaker, Berlen C., 1957; 1 (Box 4)
  - Moore, E.G., 1941-43 & n.d.'s; 9 (Box 4)
  - Morrel, John Smylie (Mrs.), 1942-52; 2 (Box 4)
  - Mount Hermon Alumni Office, 1948-57; 2 (Box 4)
  - Muncie Gear Works, Inc., 1935; 2 (Box 4)
  - National Research Council, 1946; 1 (Box 4)
  - Natl. Resources Planning Bd, n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Natl. Science Foundation, 1954 & n.d.; 2 (Box 4)
  - Natl. Speleological Society, 1949-56; 5 (Box 4)
  - Natl. Travel Club, n.d.; 1 (Box 4)
  - Nelson, Vincent E., 1954; 1 (Box 4)
  - Nesmith, James N., 1956; 1 (Box 4)
    V.U. Student Christian Assoc.
  - Newfoundland Dept. of Mines and Resources, 1947-52; 2 (Box 4)
  - Newsweek, 1943; 1 (Box 4)
  - The New York Academy of Sciences, 1955; l (Box 4)
  - Nichols, G.D., 1953; l (Box 4)
    Univ. of Ark.
  - Nichols, Ralph, 1954; 1 (Box 4)
  - Nicholson, Jake, 1955; 2 (Box 4)
  - Nilan, George, 1949; 2 (Box 4)
  - Northwestern Univ., 1944-52; 3 (Box 4)
  - A.J. Nystrom & Co., 1955; l (Box 4)
  - Oakley, Paul, 1956; l (Box 4)
  - Oak Ridge Inst, of Nuclear Studies, 1950-55; 1 (Box 4)
  - Oden, Chas R., 1948; 1 (Box 4)
  - Oden, Tom E., 1959; 1 (Box 4)
  - Office of Naval Research, 1951; l (Box 4)
  - Ogden, David A., (l); 1954 (Box 4)
  - Oldsmobile, (3); 1955-58 (Box 4)
  - Olson, C. Daswell, 1949; 1 (Box 4)
  - Outdoor Life, 1933; 2 (Box 4)
  - Ozark Biological Laboratories, 1943-55; l1 (Box 4)
  - Paschal, F.C., 1941-44; 11 (Box 5)
  - Pearson, D.E., 1956; 1 (Box 5)
  - Peebles, Wm. R., 1944; 1 (Box 5)
    -
  - The Pennsylvania St. Univ., 1958; 1 (Box 5)
  - Peoples, Joe Webb, 1931-58 & n.d.; 12 (Box 5)
  - Perry, Stuart H., n.d.; 1 (Box 5)
  - Persson, Lars E., 1960; 3 (Box 5)
  - Phelps, Grace, 1954; 2 (Box 5)
  - Phillips Petrol. Co., 1943-56; 3 (Box 5)
  - Physics Dept., 1954; 1 (Box 5)
  - Pickels, Andrew L., Jr., 1946; 2 (Box 5)
  - Pilcher, E.B., 1956; 2 (Box 5)
  - Pitner, L.E., 1943; 3 (Box 5)
  - Pomfret, John E., 1952; 2 (Box 5)
  - Pond, Franklin (Mrs.), 1957; 1 (Box 5)
  - Pond, Madeline, 1943-52; 12 (Box 5)
  - Pond, Walter, 1946; 1 (Box 5)
  - Prather, Clarke, 1941; 1 (Box 5)
  - Pritchard, J.B., 1953; 1 (Box 5)
  - Provine, Robt. Calhoun, 1945; 1 (Box 5)
  - Purdy, R.R., 1954; 1 (Box 5)
  - Qnin, Whayne S, 1944; 1 (Box 5)
  - Quinn, Alonzo, 1939-59; 7 (Box 5)
  - Rae, Bill, 1949; 1 (Box 5)
  - Rand McNally & Co., 1943; 1 (Box 5)
  - Rasmussen, E.G., 1946; 1 (Box 5)
  - Reinke, E.E., 1942; 2 (Box 5)
  - Renfroe, Audie (Mrs.), 1957; 1 (Box 5)
  - The Rice Inst., n.d.; 1 (Box 5)
  - Rich, John L., 1942; 1 (Box 5)
    Dept. of Geol. & Geography - University of Cincinnati
  - Richard, Frank A., 1958; 1 (Box 5)
  - Richards, Jack, 1948; 1 (Box 5)
  - Roark, Wade, 1955; 1 (Box 5)
  - Roberts, E.C., 1950; l (Box 5)
    Dept. of Sidgs., V.U.
  - Roberts, Joseph K., 1951; 1 (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Dan M., 1958; 1 (Box 5)
    Tenn. St. Library & Archives
  - The Univ. of Rochester, 1955; 2 (Box 5)
  - Rose, Nicholas A., n.d.; l (Box 5)
  - Rotary Club of Nashville, 1944; 1 (Box 5)
  - Royfe, A., n.d.; l (Box 5)
  - Russell Moccasin Co., 1942; l (Box 5)
  - Sampson, Edward, 1931; l (Box 5)
  - Sandia Corp., 1953; l (Box 5)
  - Sands, Lyal, 1958; l (Box 5)
  - Santos, Lucille De, 1935; l (Box 5)
  - Sarratt, CM., 1943-50; 2 (Box 5)
  - Saunders, S.J. Reginald, 1943; 1 (Box 5)
  - Sayles, A.E., 1947-54; 2 (Box 5)
  - Schlinitz, Frank R., 1955; 1 (Box 5)
  - Schneider, Michael C., i960; 1 (Box 5)
  - School of Mines, 1943; l (Box 5)
  - Schreiber, Nicholas J.A., 1949; 1 (Box 5)
  - Science, 1952; l (Box 5)
  - Science Division - V.U., 1959; l (Box 5)
  - Scruggs, Frances, 1940; l (Box 5)
    V.U. News Release Office
  - Seal Incorporated, 1943-47; 3 (Box 5)
  - Sears, Roebuck & Co., n.d.; l (Box 5)
  - Segal, M., 1953 & n.d.; 2 (Box 5)
  - Seiler Instrument Co., 1947-49; 2 (Box 5)
  - Seyfert, Carl K., 1956; 1 (Box 5)
  - Shaffer, Louise B., 1950; 1 (Box 5)
  - Shearon, Will H., 1948; 1 (Box 5)
  - Sheean, Jack, 1954; 1 (Box 5)
  - Shoup, C.S., 1950 & n.d.; 2 (Box 5)
  - Shull, Richard, 1957; 1 (Box 5)
  - Shurtleff, Malcolm C., 1952; 1 (Box 5)
  - Sifford, Joseph, 1943; 1 (Box 5)
  - Silon, Charles I., 1948-49; 2 (Box 5)
  - Sipe, H. Craig, 1958; 1 (Box 5)
    Director, Summer Inst. - Peahoi
  - Slack, Francis G., 1947-58 & n.d.; 6 (Box 5)
  - Slade, Hipp & Meloy, Inc., 1959; 2 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Lee Irvin, 1945; 1 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Ollie, 1945-; 5 (Box 5)
  - Snelgrove, A.K., 1936-39; 3 (Box 5)
  - Snyder, Frank, 1951-52; 2 (Box 5)
  - Society of Emploration Geo-physicists, n.d.; 1 (Box 5)
  - Sorrwar, Gholam, 1959; 1 (Box 5)
  - Southeastern Geology, 1960; 1 (Box 5)
  - The Southern Assoc. for the Advancement of Science, 1942; 1 (Box 5)
  - Southern Ferro Alloys Co., 1945; l (Box 5)
  - Southern Methodist Univ., 1934-55; 2 (Box 5)
  - Southern Saddlery Co., 1937; 1 (Box 5)
  - South Georgia Rug Cleaners, 1956; 1 (Box 5)
  - Spencer Lens Co., 1943; 2 (Box 5)
  - Standard Oil Development Co., 1948-52; 4 (Box 5)
  - Stearns, Richard, 1950; 1 (Box 5)
  - Steelman, J.R., 1939; 1 (Box 5)
    U.S. Conciliation Service
  - The Stevens, 1946; 2 (Box 5)
  - Stobbe, Helen, 1953; 1 (Box 5)
    Dept. of Geoll & Geogr. -Smith College
  - Stockdale, Paris B., 1943-53; 13 (Box 5)
  - Stocking, George W., 1956; 1 (Box 5)
  - Stoddart, P.C., 1949; 1 (Box 5)
  - Stonborough, John J., 1939; 2 (Box 5)
  - Stone Construction Co., 1953; 1 (Box 5)
  - Stone, Walter L., 1944; 1 (Box 5)
    Council of Community Agencies
  - Stovall, J. Willis, 1927; 2 (Box 5)
  - Stow, Marcellus H., 1951; 1 (Box 5)
    Wash. & Lee Univ. - Dept. of Geology
  - Stow, Steve, n.d.'a; 3 (Box 5)
  - Survey of Selected Engineering Personnel, 1949; 1 (Box 5)
  - Sutherland, Jane, 1957; 1 (Box 5)
    Registrar - V.U.
  - Swingle, George, 1954; 1 (Box 5)
    Dept. of Geol. & Geogr. - U.T. Knoxville
  - Tanner, Willian F., n.d.; 1 (Box 5)
  - Temple, Thomas B., 1953; 1 (Box 5)
  - Tenn. Academy of Science, 1942; 1 (Box 5)
    (Journal of the T.S.A.)
  - Tenn. College Assoc., 1944; 1 (Box 5)
    (Provident Ins. Program)
  - Tenn. Hospital Service Assoc., n.d.; 1 (Box 5)
  - Tenn. Polytechnic Inst., 1955; 1 (Box 5)
  - Tenn. Valley Authority, 1948-58; 10 (Box 5)
  - Texas, Univ. of, 1950-53; 2 (Box 5)
  - Thin Section Lab., 1961; 1 (Box 5)
  - Thorn, W.T., Jr., 1931-34; 7 (Box 5)
  - Thurston Supply Co., 1946; 1 (Box 5)
  - Time Magazine, 1953-61; 2 (Box 5)
  - Tippens, Clark B., 1942; 1 (Box 5)
  - The Tulane Univ. of La., 1946-49; 3 (Box 5)
  - J.M. Tull Metal & Supply Co., 1948; 1 (Box 5)
  - Turner, Hill, 1934-43; 4 (Box 5)
    V.U. Alumni Secretary
  - Union Carbide, 1952; 1 (Box 5)
  - Waldrop, Robert S., 1950-52; 3 (Box 5)
    V.U. Dean of Students
  - Walder, Curtis H., 1954; 1 (Box 5)
  - Wall, Pemberton B., 1953; l (Box 5)
  - Wanless, Harold A., 1949; l (Box 5)
  - War Dept., 1943; 2 (Box 5)
  - Ward's Natl. Science Estab., 1943-52; 9 (Box 5)
  - War Manpower Commission, 1943 & n.d.; 3 (Box 5)
  - Warthin, A.S., Jr., 1943; 1 (Box 5)
    Wagner Free Inst, of Science
  - Washington & Lee Univ., 1958; 2 (Box 5)
  - Washington Univ., 1957; l (Box 5)
  - Watkins, Anna B., 1948; 1 (Box 5)
  - Weakley, S.A., 1947; 1 (Box 5)
  - Weaver, Herbert, 1955-56; 4 (Box 5)
  - Weaver, Herbert (Mrs.), 1960; 1 (Box 5)
  - Webb, John H., 1946-50; 2 (Box 5)
  - Weber, Jack, 1950; 1 (Box 5)
  - Weems, Eliru J., 1949; 1 (Box 5)
  - Welder, F.A., 1959; 1 (Box 5)
    Northeast La. St. College
  - Wells, Francis G., 1929; 1 (Box 5)
  - Werthan Bag Corp., 1942; 1 (Box 5)
  - Western Mineral Exchange, n.d.; 1 (Box 5)
  - Westinghouse Electric & Manuf., 1928; 2 (Box 5)
  - White, Carlton, 1956; 1 (Box 5)
  - Whitehead Metal Products Co., 1948; 1 (Box 5)
  - Whitesides, Virgil S., Jr., 1954; 2 (Box 5)
  - Whitney, R.H., 1949; 1 (Box 5)
  - Who's Who in America, 1955; 1 (Box 5)
  - John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1942-59; 10 (Box 5)
  - Willard, Bradford, 1959; 1 (Box 5)
    Dept. of Geol. - Lehigh Univ.
  - Willard, Carolyn Evins, 1953; 1 (Box 5)
  - Williams, David M., 1957; 1 (Box 5)
  - Williams, Overton, 1942-57; 6 (Box 5)
  - Williamson, R.M., 1942; 1 (Box 5)
    Weather Bureau
  - Willoughby's, 1943; l (Box 5)
  - Wilson, C.W., 1953; l (Box 5)
  - Wilson, Robt. L., 1959; 1 (Box 5)
  - Wilson Truck Co., 1955; 5 (Box 5)
  - Wood, Lewis F., 1948; 1 (Box 5)
  - Wynne Precision Co., 1946; 1 (Box 5)
  - Wyoming, Univ. of, 1950; 1 (Box 5)
  - First name only --- 1 letter (Box 5)
- Incoming Correspondence by Subject
  - Chancellor (Box 6)
  - Crawford, Meredith, Dean (Box 6)
  - Davidson, Philip, Dean (Box 6)
  - Geography (A.S.T.P.) (Box 7)
  - G.S.A. (Box 7)
  - Junior College Advisors (Box 7,8)
  - Natural Sciences, Division of (Box 8)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa (Box 8)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 8)
  - Pomfret, John E., Dean (Box 8)
  - Pre-Meteorological (Box 8)
  - Princeton-V.U. Program (Box 8)
  - Science Fair (Box 8)
  - Semester System (Box 8)
  - Shahan, Ewing P. (Box 8)
  - Shop Committee (Box 8)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 8)
  - Smith, George M, Dean (Box 8)
  - Smoke Abatement (Box 8)
  - Stambaugh, John H. (Box 8)
  - YMCA (Box 9)
  - Veterans' Council (Box 9)
  - Veterans' Council (Box 10)
- Minutes, Reports, Correspondence arranged under the subject headings listed earlier, and miscellaneous materials dealing with Vanderbilt University, all arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Advisees - 1936-37 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Advisors - Advisees - 1928-45 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Advisors - Advisees - n.d.'s (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Athletic Committee - 1942-46 (Box 6, Folder 4,5)
  - Branscomb Dinner, Dec. 20, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Branscomb Professorship, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Buford, Mr. James L. - Senior College Material, 1952-53 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cars and Trucks - 1929-34 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Chancellor - Correspondence, 1930-64 (Box 6, Folder 10, 11)
  - Columbia Military Academy Evaluation, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Crawford, Meredith P. (Dean) - Correspondence, 1949-52 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Davidson, Philip (Dean) - Correspondence, 1942-52 (Box 6, Folder l4)
  - Faculty Advisory Program Committee - 1952-56 (Box 6, Folder 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20)
  - Faculty Ciub, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Handbook (Writeup of Faculty Meetings), 1943 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Minutes, Duplicates - Bept,. 23, 1941 - June 8, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Minutes Duplicates - June 20, 1945 - June 4, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Facility Minutes Duplicates - July 6, 1948 - June 2, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Minutes Duplicates, Jan. 9, 1951 - June 6, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Minutes Duplicates - Sept. 19, 1952 - Dec. 8, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Facuity Minutes Duplicates, Jan. 12,, 1954 - Mar. 2, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Minutes Duplicates - Mar. 9, 1955 - June, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Minutes Appendices - 1945- -56 (Box 7, Folder (8, 9, 10))
  - Faculty Resolutions (Death and Retirement) - 1943-64 (Box 7, Folder (ll))
  - Geography (A.s.T.P. - Correspondence) - 1943-44 (Box 7, Folder (12, 13))
  - Q.S.A. - Southeastern Section - 1954-63 (Box 7, Folder (l4, 15, 16))
  - Instruction and Guidance Committee - 1932-41 (Box 7, Folder (17))
  - Joint Faculty-Student Committee on Student Union Affairs (Box 7, Folder (18))
  - J.U.L. Committee - 1951-61 (Box 7, Folder (19, 20))
  - Junior College Advisors - 1952-57 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Junior College Advisors - 1952-57 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Junico and Senior College Committee - 1936-37 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (Appendices), College of Arts and Science Faculty - 1943-58 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Natural Sciences, Division of - 1929-50 (Box 8, Folder 4, 5)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa - 1939-64 (Box 8, Folder 6, 7)
  - PBK - Key-Reporter - 1953-66 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Phi Beta Kappa - 1955-66 (Box 8, Folder 9, 10)
  - Poll of Faculty Members - April, 1953 (Re: Revised advisory and Registrafc Procedures *See BOX 10 (Box 8)
  - Pomfret, John E. (Dean) - Correspondence - 1941-42 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pre-Meteorological -- CorreSpondence - 1943-45 (Box 8, Folder 12, 13, 14)
  - Princeton-Vanderbilt Program - 194l (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Reprints from Flower and Cook Observatory (Univ. of Penn.) - 1964-65 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Science Fair - 1957-58 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Semester System - 1947-55 (Box 8, Folder l8)
  - Senior College Committee Minutes - 1935-57 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Shahan, Ewing P. (Dean) (Correspondence, Misc.) - 1951-60 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Shop Committee -- i960 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Sigma Xi - 1944-54 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Sigma Xi - 1955-66 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Smith, George M. (Dean) Correspondence - 1950-56 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Smoke Abatement - 1939-46 (Box 8, Folder 25, 26)
  - Stambaugh, John H. (Vice-Chancellor) - Correspondence - 1956-62 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Student Christian Assoc. - 1947-54 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Student Publication Board - 1964-66 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Study of American Men of Science - n.d.'s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Tenn. Academy of Science - General Correspondence, misc. - 1934-63 (Box 9, Folder 4-9)
  - Tenn. Academy of Science - Exec. Committee 1962863 (Box 9, Folder 10, 11, 12)
  - Tenn. Geological Surrey 1933-59 (Box 9, Folder 13, 14)
  - Tenn. Junior Academy of Science, Oak Ridge - 1960-63 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Tenn. Surrey Work - Correspondence 1939-57 (Box 9, Folder l6)
  - Thruston Collection, 1957, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Unirersity Senate - 1959-64 (Box 9, Folder l8)
  - Vanderbilt Campus DriTe, $30 Million for 1961-66 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Vanderbilt Committee - Names 196I (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Vanderbilt Committee - General 1961-62 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Vanderbilt University Press - 1941-56 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Veterans Council - 1944-45 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Veterans Council - 1944-45 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - World Student Serrice Fund, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - TMCA, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Zerfoss, Tom, Dr. - ca., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Poll of Faculty Members (Re: Rerised Advisory & Registration Procedures), April, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 5, 6)
  - Dr. Jewell: Class Notes, Wartime (Box 11)
  - Dr. Jewell: Consulting Work with W.C. Sparks (Box 11)
  - Dr. Jewell: Geology Library (Box 11)
  - Dr. Jewell: Miscellaneous Photos (Box 11)
  - Dr. Jewell: Personal Papers (Box 11)
  - Dean Nora Chaffin: Study of Vocational Choices of Vanderbilt Women Students, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
  - field Trips, Geology 201: 1942--1954 (Box 11)
  - Geology Department Schedules, 1945--1968 (Box 11)
  - Comprehensive Exams, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Exams: General Historical Geology (Box 11)
  - Pre-Me terology (Box 11)
  - Minerology (Box 11)
  - Economic Geology Field Maps and Notes, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Grade Record, Geology, 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Class Rolls (Box 12)
  - General Geology, 1949-1967 (Box 12)
  - Geology 302 1958-1961 (Box 12)
  - Geology 415 (Minerology), 1929-1958 (Box 12)
  - Geology 411 (Economic Geology), 1949-1967 (Box 12)
  - Lecture Notes (Box 12)
  - Engineering Geology (Box 12)
  - General Geology (Box 12)
  - Geology 201 Lab Exercise (Box 12)
  - " " Manual (Manuscript) (Box 12)
  - Historical Geology (Box 12)
  - " " (old notes) (Box 12)
  - Original Notes (Engineering Geology) (Box 12)
  - Petrology (lectures) (Box 12)
  - " " (laboratory) (Box 12)
  - Physical Geology lectures (Box 12)
  - Sanitary Engineers (lectures), 1936 (Box 12)
  - Structural Geology (Box 12)
  - " " (Willis-Princeton) (Box 12)
  - Tests: (Box 12)
  - Economic Geology, 1930-1937, 1942 (Box 12)
  - Geology 201, 1926-1936, 1940, 1942 (Box 12)
  - " Lab, 1925-1931, 1936 (Box 12)
  - Minerology, 1931 (Box 12)
  - Petrography, 1927, 1931-1932, 1937, 1939 (Box 12)
  - Structure, 1927 (Box 12)
  - U. S. Geology, 1929, 1931, 1952 (Box 12)